American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to George Ord, Philadelphia, Feb. 23, 1828; 9x7; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    A.L.S.: Jos. Sabine. 2p.and add.,end. by W.Vaughan. Have complete set of APS publications.
  - A[lexander] H. Everett to John Vaughan, February 28, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Everett, Alexander Hill, 1790-1847
    Madrid, 2 pp. A.L.S. Has purchased for the A.P.S., for $8, the printed Letters of Cortes.
  - E. Littell to John Vaughan, [Philadelphia], March 6, 1828; 4 15/16" x 7 13/16"; Littell, Eliakim, 1797-1870
    1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. In the name of Stephen Elliott, presents to the A.P.S. the first number of the Southern Review.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, London, March 12, 1828; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.A.Drummond-Hay. 2p. Thanks for APS publication. Will complete the publications given to the APS if any are lacking.
  - Report of committee on G[eorge] Ord's paper on birds, March 21, 1828; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: S. George Morton, Charles Pickering, and Richard Harlan. 2p.,end. Cf. Minutes, p.579. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 292 ff.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 29, 1828; 10x8; Académie des inscriptions & belles-lettres (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Dacier. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, March 29, 1828; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: Cuvier. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Report of the committee on Dr. [Richard] Harlan's paper on the rattlesnake, April 4, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Charles Pickering, B. H. Coates, G[eorge] Ord. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Daniel Brent to John Vaughan, April 11, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Department of State, Washington, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Is sending to the A.P.S. designated congressional documents.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, April 14, 1828; 9x7-1/2; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.H.Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for APS publication.
  - Henry J[ames] Anderson to John Vaughan, April 21, 1828; 7 13/16" x 9 1/2"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - William Zollickoffer to the Secretary of the A.P.S., April 27, 1828; 4 15/16" x 7 5/8"; Zollickoffer, William, 1792-1853
    Baltimore, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to know whether his Materia Medica of the United States was received by the A.P.S. If not, will forward another copy.
  - Letter to Peter DuPonceau, April 30, 1828; 8 1/2" x 13"; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert de Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834
    Paris, Typewritten copy of L. 1p. In French. Accompanied by translation. Introduces Henry Ternaux; asks that he be presented to the Philosophical society. Presented by J. Bennett Nolan.
  - Edward Jones to John Vaughan, May 1, 1828; 7 13/16" x 9 9/16"; Jones, Edward
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Assures Mr. Vaughan that custom house rules as to books are to be given "the most liberal interpretation of which the law is susceptible."
  - Daniel Brent to John Vaughan, May 14, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841
    Librarian to the A.P.S., Department of State, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will send to the A.P.S. a set of the Secret Journals of Congress.
  - [Royal] Horticultural Society to George Ord, May 19, 1828; 7 1/2" x 8 15/16"; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    [London], 1 p. and endorsement. L..S.: J[oh]n Sabine, Secretary. Presents to the A.P.S.: Transactions, VII, pt. 2.
  - John Sergeant to John Vaughan, May 19, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will supply the A.P.S. with a copy of the work son silk worms if the secretary of the treasury fails to do so.
  - C. C. Rafn to the American Philosophical Society, May 27, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 9/16"; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, 6 pp. A.L.S. Details concerning his work on the pre-Columbian history of North America. Encloses copies of the chief works of the Royal Northern Society of Antiquaries for the years 1825-1827.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], June 2, 1828; 10x8; Nirderstitter,
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards volumes from Berlin.
  - W[illia]m Marsden to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 11, 1828; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Marsden, William, 1754-1836
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a set of his published works, bound in five volumes. Titles enumerated.
  - C. C. Rafn to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, President of the A.P.S., June 12, 1828; 8 1/2" x 10"; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, 1 p. A.L.S. Forwards information concerning the Royal Northern Society of Antiquaries.
  - Society of Antiquaries of Scotland to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 17, 1828; 8" x 9 3/4"; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S.: E. W. Drummond-Hay, Secretary. Is forwarding to the A.P.S. a series of publications of the Society of Antiquaries "from its Institution to the present time... "
  - Tho[mas] Thornely to John Vaughan, June 19, 1828; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Thornely, Thomas
    Liverpool, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a "companion to the Almance..."
  - Henry James Anderson to ----, June 26, 1828; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    New York, 2pp. A.L.S. With regard to revision of format [of A.P.S. Transactions?].
  - Letter to ---- ----, June 29, 1828; 7" x 8 3/4"; Dantas, José Maria Dantas, 1772-1836
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American philosophical society.
  - Jos[eph] Gilpin to John Vaughan, June 30, 1828; 8" x 9 3/4"; Gilpin, Joseph
    Kentmere, 3 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Copy. Regarding "Mr. Preston of England's intended bequest of his Library to the philadelphia Library."
  - Report of committee on the article on birds by C.L.Bonaparte, July 18, 1828; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: George Ord, Charles Pickering, and Richd. Harlan. 3p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.582. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 383 ff.
  - Philip Tidyman to the President and members of the A.P.S., August 5, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Tidyman, Philip
    German Town, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., in the name of Duke Bernard of Saxe-Weimar; the latter's Travels in the United States. FILM403 FRAME124
  - Letter to Baron von Schuckmann, Aug. 22, 1828; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau. 2p.and end. Cf. Minutes, pp.582-583. FILM 403 FRAME 147
  - Geo[rge] Ticknor to John Vaughan, Boston, August 23, 1828; 7 3/8" x 8 15/16"; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 7, 1828; 8x5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Concerning donations from the Académie des sciences of the institut de France.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Sept. 10, 1828; 10x8; Pereira de Azambuja, Jacob Frederico Torlade, 1788-1847
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications from the Lisbon academia real das sciencias.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., 1828 September 10; Santarém, Manuel Francisco de Barros e Sousa, Visconde de, 1791-1856
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Sept. 15, 1828; 10x8; Casado Giraldes, J. P. C. (Joaquim Pedro Cardozo)
    Havre, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Forwards publications and makes inquiries of U.S. geography.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 16, 1828; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Girard. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - George Ticknor to John K. Kane, September 21, 1828; 7 5/16" x 8 15/16"; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Henry J[ame]s Anderson to John Vaughan, September 27, 1828; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of a letter containing bill of lading for the books. "The type which I have sent on can be retained for the use of the Society.. ."
  - P. Pedersen to John Vaughan, October 10, 1828; 7 5/8" x 11 13/16"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Librarian to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a number of books and prints to the A.P.S., in the name of the King of Denmark.
  - Report of committee on paper on insects by [Nicholas Marcellus] Hentz, Oct. 17, 1828; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Charles Pickering, Richd. Harlan and Zaccheus Collins. 1p.and end. Cf, Minutes, p.585. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 458 ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1828; 10x8; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.: E.Everett. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of committee on paper by Graberg de Hemsoe [sic] on Arabic dialect, Oct. 18, 1828; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, Zaccheus Collins, and Jos.Hopkinson. 2p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.585.
  - Letter to Elisha J. Abel, Oct. 31, 1828; 10x8; Great Falls Manufacturing Company
    Somersworth, L.S.: C.C.Wolcott, agent. 2p. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 55.) Concerning the Brewster spinners. On same sheet with letter from Mease to [Sanseer Mfg. Co.]; Nov.11,1831: and [Sanseer Mfg.Co] Advertisement; Oct. 14, 1828.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 31, 1828; 10x8; New-York Historical Society
    New York, A.L.S.: Jno.Delafield, jr. 1p.and add., end. Thanks for publication.
  - Report of committee on Rafn's letter from the antiquarian society of northern antiqities., 1828 ca. October; American Philosophical Society.
    The A.P.S. committee reporting on Rafn's letter recommends purchase of two copies of the publications of the Icelandic Antiquarian Society at Copenhagen that Mr. Rafn informed them about, once they are published. The committee also recommends their promotion to other American literary societies, as well as monies to help them subscribe to the publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 6, 1828; 8x5; Real Academia de la Historia
    L.S.: F. de P. Quadrado. 2p., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the APS, Nov. 6, 1828; 10x8; Quadrado y de Roó, Francisco de Paula
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.,end. In Spanish. Forwards publications of the royal historical society of Spain.
  - Albert Gallatin to John Vaughan, November 7, 1828; 8" x 10"; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    Washington, 3 pp. Regarding maps wanted by the Department of State in connection with diplomatic negotiations with England.
  - Ja[me]s Renwick to J[ohn] K. Kane, November 8, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Renwick, James, 1792-1863
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Columbia College, New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - James Brown to P[eter] S. DuPonceau, November 12, 1828; 8" x 10"; Brown, James, 1766-1835
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. 8" x 10" A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S. a work presented by the author.
  - American Philosophical Society to Samuel Brown, November 21, 1828; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. D.S.: Franklin Beache, Secretary. Returns thanks for pamphlet, Séance publique annuelle des quatre academies, 1828.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1828; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Rod.I. Murchison. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1828; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
  - Albert Gallatin to John Vaughan, November 22, 1828; 7 3/4" x 10"; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of letter of the 16th., and nineteen maps mentioned therein.
  - Henry Ja[me]s Anderson to John Vaughan, November 30, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Safe arrival of books (i.e., A.P.S. Transactions) and deposit thereof with Carvill and Company. Expects little or no sale.
  - Letter to George Ord, Philadelphia, Dec. 2, 1828; 9x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.E.Bicheno. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for APS publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 2, 1828; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos.Sabine. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 4, 1828; 10x8; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Robinson. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Report of the building committee regarding arrangement with Athenaeum about north basement room, December 5, 1828; 6 1/2" x 6 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan, J[ohn] K. Kane, W[illia]m Strickland.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1828; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add.,end. Praise of science.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 12, 1828; 8x5; Royal Astronomical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W. S. Stratford. 1p.and add.and end. Thanks for APS publication forwarded by W.Vaughan.
  - List of books presented by Frederick Adelung to the American Philosophical Society, December 19, 1828; 7 7/8" x 12 7/8"; Adelung, Friedrich von, 1768-1843
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp. and endorsement. D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 587.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 19, 1828; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S. Cuvier. 1p.and add.,end. In French Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 20, 1828; 10x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Suggests using Franklin's head on new seal for the Society. See Minutes, p.587. FILM54-67 FRAME 76
  - Letter to John Vaughan, librarian of the A.P.S., Dec. 24, 1828; 8" x 10"; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    A(?) .L.S: John Robison, secretary. 1p. and end. Calls attention to the Keith biennial prize medal offered by the Council of the Society.
  - Letter to the president or secretary of the Asiatic society of Calcutta, Dec. 29, 1828; 8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Letterpress c. of L. 1p. Sends APS Transactions for their library.
  - Memorandum concerning Rafn's communication about Norse relics in North America, Dec., [1828]; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 54.) On same sheet as letter from DuPonceau to J.Vaughan; Dec. 17, 1828.
  - Letter to, 1828 December; Adelung, Friedrich von, 1768-1843
    Letter expressing his gratitude and says he is sending a little package of books to the A.P.S., and calls attention to the works on Russia.
  - Announcement of the Transactions, vol. III, part 2, new series, 1828; American Philosophical Society.
    See Oversize Box
  - Sam[uel] Belton to John Vaughan, January 1, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Belton, Samuel
    German town, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns thanks for his election to membership in the A.P.S.
  - Engagement to sup together on the sixtieth anniv[ersar]y of the [Amercian Philosophical] Society, January 2, 1829; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Of value for autographs.
  - Albert Gallatin to John Vaughan, January 2, 1829; 8" x 9 7/8"; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. A.L.S. Returns designated maps, which have not been used, together with receipts therefor.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 3, 1829; 12-1/2x8; Royal Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thomas Young. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to Tho[ma]s P. Jones, January 22, 1829; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of documents upon the raising of silk worms. Encloses list of deficiencies in A.P.S. set of public documents since 1817.
  - Invoice of books purchased by order of John Vaughan, Librarian of the A.P.S., January 29, 1829; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    ...Paris, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.D.Signed: George Ord. Books purchased in Paris by Mr. Ord. Value, 886 franc, 95 sous. Invoice enclosed in Ord to Vaughan, 1-29-1829.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., January 29, 1829; 8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to books purchased in Paris for the library of the A.P.S.
  - Philip Tidyman to John Vaughan, January 30, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/8"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 1 p., address and endorsement. Donates to the A.P.S. a number of books, listed herein.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 31, 1829; 9-3/4x8; Cooper, William, 1798?-1864
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning bones of megalonyx owned by Dorfeuille and hopes the APS will get them Refers to Jefferson. For printed description of these bones, see: Journal.Acad.of Nat.Sci,Vol.VI,p.269. FILM199 FRAME 765
  - W. H. DeLancey to F[ranklin] Bache, February 6, 1829; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; De Lancey, William Heathcote, 1797-1865
    Secretary of the A.P.S., ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. Emcloses $15 in payment of dues.
  - P. Pedersen to J[ohn] Vaughan, February 6, 1829; 4 15/16" x 7 7/8"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates small Russian coin to the A.P.S. Work of C. C. Rafn on North American antiquities.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., February 11, 1829; 8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Concerning books, to the value of 178 francs, 75 sous, purchased for himself but forwarded to the A.P.S. and included in their account.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, February 12, 1829; 8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Case of books shipped to A.P.S. on board the Francois I. Invoice of 1,065 francs, 70 Sous.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 28, 1829; 8" x 10"; Fischer von Waldheim, Gotthelf, 1771-1853
    Moscow, A.L.S. 1p. and end. A.L.S. In French Donations for the Society.
  - Invoice of books purchased in Paris for the American Philosophical Society. Total of 886 francs, 95 sous., February, 1829; 8 5/8" x 13 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    and shipped on the Francois I in By George Ord. 4 pp. D. Books valued at 886 francs, 95 sous.
  - Books sent to [American] Phil[osophical] Society [from Paris], February-June, 1829-1831; 4 7/8" x 6 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Value: 1,176 francs, 90 sous, calculated as $227.42.
  - Letter to J.R. Poinsett, 1829 March 3; Bustamenti, Jose Maria, Don
    Bustamenti acknowledges his election to the A.P.S..
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 4, 1829; 9x7; Agricultural & Horticultural Society of India
    Calcutta, L.S.: W. Carey. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - A[lexander] H. Everett to John Vaughan, March 5, 1829; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Everett, Alexander Hill, 1790-1847
    Madrid, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Royal Academy of History of Madrid wishes to renew correspondence with the A.P.S. and has sent a parcel containing its Transactions and other publications.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., March 5, 1829; 5" x 8"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to additional books bought in Paris for the library of the A.P.S. Value, 55 francs, 70 sous.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, March 10, 1829; 5" x 8"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has purchased a copy of Musaeum Hermeticum for A.P.S. Price, 4 francs.
  - Invoice of books sent through Mr. Dobson [to the American Philosophical Society], March 10, April 28, 1829, 1830; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. D. Value: 92 francs, 50 sous.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Aug. 7/19, 1829; 10x8; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    St. Petersbourg, L.S.: Fuss. 1p. and add., end. In French. Thanks for APS publications.
  - Basil Hall to John Vaughan, March 13, 1829; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Hall, Basil, 1788-1844
    Edinburgh, 2pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to exchange of publications between Edinburgh Antiquarian Society and A.P.S.
  - Letter to E. Nutley, 1829 March 30; Nutley, E.
    Says he will pay the sum named.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March, 1829; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Erman. 1p. and end. In Latin. Forwards publications.
  - Report of committee on [Richard] Harlan's paper on rattlesnake poison, April 3, 1829; 3-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.Pickering, B.H.Coates and R.E. Griffith. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.590. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 300 ff.
  - Report of committee on the making of meteorological observations, April 3, 1829; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: William Hembel, F. Nichols, and Sam. Geo. Morton. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.591.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1829 April 6; Vaux, George
    Vaux writes to John Vaughan to request acknowledgment that the A.P.S. Library has accepted his donation of 3 volumes of the Theological Repository.
  - Lease issued to Athenaeum for rooms in Philosophical hall for five years, April 10, 1829; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    D.S: Franklin Bache, sec. 2p. and end. Seal. ---- Another copy signed by Wm. Mcllhenney secy [Athenaeum].
  - W[illia]m Cooper to John Vaughan, April 10, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Cooper, William, 1798?-1864
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding Vaughan's membership in the Lyceum of Natural History. Has been correcting proof-sheets of [Charles Lucien] Bonaparte's paper on grouse.
  - Report of committee on paper by [Philip Houlbrooke] Nicklin on shells, April 13, 1829; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Eglesfeld Griffith and C.Pickering. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.591. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 395 ff.
  - Report of committee on [Richard] Harlan's paper on birds, April 16, 1829; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C. Pickering, B.H.Coates, and R. Eglesfeld Griffith. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.591. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 464-465, 466 ff.
  - American Philosophical Society to Joseph Roberts, April 17, 1829; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society